okay I've got Camille here and she is
going to do a dead stop reset pushup and
one thing I want to point out so she's
laying on the ground and she's got her
hands closed she's not out wide like
most people want to do most women
especially will want to do push-ups like
this with their elbows out and out wide
she's got her hands closer and tucked in
that makes it significantly harder right
off the bat but what she's going to do
here is squeeze her glutes into a
posterior pillow tilt see how that
flattened out her spine okay go for
it okay come down good she stops resets
squeeze the glute again come up
again good um stop okay so see you can
see so relax relax you can see this
lumbar spine here is significantly
extended and then she squeezes the
glutes into posterior pelvic tilt and it
flattens out now and now good so this
makes it way harder to do a pushup I
think Camille can do like 10 normal
push-ups right but getting three this
way is really really hard so but I like
this because it builds good lumbo pelvic
pelvic hip uh complex mechanics um which
is just a fancy way of saying the lumbar
spine doesn't hyperextend the hips don't
sag and that's a common flaw with the
pushup so give these a try and let me
know what you think